MD JAHID HASAN

W O R D P R E S S D E V E L O P E R





+8801771749213



+8801960576371



mdjahidhasan919@gmail.com



Satai, Boshotpur, Sharsha, Jashore, Bangladesh-7432



https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-jahid-hasan-584712243/



https://github.com/hmjahid



https://hmjahid.netlify.app/

SKILLS

- · Problem-Solving
- Web Design
- WordPress Development and Theme Customization
- Experienced in DIVI and Elementor Page Builder
- Front-End Coding
- Version Control System (Git)
- Designing Tools (Figma, Canva)
- Project Management Tools Trello
- Strong Communication
- Proficient in Office Applications
- Familiar and Comfortable with Unix-like OSs (FreeBSD, Linux) and server operating systems like Proxmox, TrueNAS Scale, Ubuntu Server, Centos, RHEL etc.
- Comfortable with Docker Containerization
- Comfortable with Virtualization Technology.
- Familiar with Kubernetes Orchestration and Cloud service AWS.
- Familiar with server monitoring tools Prometheus, Grafana, Nagios and Configuration Management Tool Ansible

EDUCATION

SECONDARY SCHOOL

Science (GPA-5.0)

Satai A.C.I United Secondary School

Passing Year: 2011

HIGHER SECONDARY (GPA-4.4)

Science (GPA-4.4) Dr. Afiluddin College Passing Year : 2013

LANGUAGE

- Bengali (Native)
- English (Proficient)
- Hindi (Working Proficiency)
- Malay (Working Proficiency)

PROFILE

I am a qualified and professional web developer with experience in website design, front-end development, wordpress website design, wordpress website development, wordpress theme customization, woocommerce website design and development . I inherit strong creative and analytical skills. I am detail oriented and a hardworker. Team player with an eye for details. I am well and love working in team environment as well as utilizing self initiative.

EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR WORDPRESS DEVELOPER

WebFix Lab, Dhaka, Banagladesh - Remote July, 2023 - Present

- I am responsible for developing, maintaining, and updating websites on WordPress for a diverse range of clients.
- My role also involves optimizing website performance, following SEO best practices, and staying updated with the latest industry trends
- I am committed to maintaining strict confidentiality and professionalism with all client projects and information.

CNC OPERATOR, MACHINIST AND PROGRAMMER

Nichima Precision Engineering Sdn. Bhd., Penang, Malaysia April, 2016 - April, 2022

- I worked as 2axis CNC Lathe operator, machinist and programmer
- Led a small team of 5-6 people
- Also worked as 3 axis CNC Milling operator and machinist

OFFICE ASSISTANT CUM COMPUTER OPERATOR

Nichima Precision Engineering Sdn. Bhd., Penang, Malaysia March, 2016 - April, 2016

- Assisted HR manager in preparing payroll
- Assisted sales department to entry data in database
- I also worked in QC department as a QC Inspector

COURSE

DATABASE PROGRAMMING

Bangladesh Technical Education Board (BTEB) July, 2013 - December, 2013

MASTERCAM NC PROGRAMMING

IME CADCAM Training Centre, Penang, Malaysia October, 2018